Guide to the United States War Department correspondence and records regarding Indian affairs and activities with Indian nations,1798-1874.
United States War Department correspondence and records regarding Indian affairs and activities with Indian nations,1798-1874.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
United States War Department correspondence and records regarding Indian affairs and activities with Indian nations, 1798-1874.
9188
United States.War Dept.
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Typed transcripts of correspondence and records of activities with Indian nations. Transcripts include information on Indian census, Indian removal, reports from Indian agencies, United States policy, trade regulations, emigration, crime, and treaties. Many of the reports are from Indian agents to commanding officers or superintendents of the Office of Indian Affairs, some correspondence giving instructions to agents. Includes an index.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Typed transcripts of correspondence and records of activities with Indian nations. Transcripts include information on Indian census, Indian removal, reports from Indian agencies, United States policy, trade regulations, emigration, crime, and treaties. Many of the reports are from Indian agents to commanding officers or superintendents of the Office of Indian Affairs, some correspondence giving instructions to agents. Includes an index.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United States.; Belknap, William W.(William Worth), 1829-1890.; Burdett, Samuel S.(Samuel Swinfin), 1836-1914.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Clark, William, 1770-1838.; Crazy Horse, ca. 1842-1877.; Ewing, George Washington, 1803-1866.; Herring, E.(Elbert), 1777-1876.; Lee, George Washington Custis, 1832-1913.; Leeper, Mathew.; McGillycuddy, Valentine, 1849-1939.; Meigs, Return Jonathan, 1740-1823.; Pike, Albert, 1809-1891.; Rector, Elias.; Reed, Thomas B.(Thomas Brackett), 1839-1902.; Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888.; Stevens, Isaac Ingalls, 1818-1862.; Taylor, Ezra B.(Ezra Booth), 1823-1912.; Townsend, E. D.(Edward Davis), 1817-1893.; Huntington Free Library.; United States.Office of Indian Affairs.; United States.Office of Indian Affairs.Red Cloud Agency.
Subjects:
Indians of North America.; Indians of North America--Alcohol use.; Indian captivities.; Indians of North America--Census.; Indians of North America--Commerce.; Indians of North America--Cultural assimilation.; Indians of North America--Government relations.; Indians of North America--Great Plains.; Indians of North America--Iowa.; Indians of North America--Kansas.; Indians of North America--Michigan.; Indians of North America--Missouri.; Indians of North America--Missouri River Valley.; Indians of North America--Montana.; Indians of North America--Oregon.; Indians of North America--Texas.; Indians of North America--Utah.; Indians of North America--Washington (State).; Indians of North America--Wisconsin.; Indians of North America--Migrations.; Indians of North America--Missions.; Indians of North America; Mormons.; Blackfoot Indians.; Caddo Indians.; Cherokee Indians.; Chickasaw Indians.; Choctaw Indians.; Comanche Indians.; Creek Indians.; Dakota Indians.; Fox Indians.; Iowa Indians.; Kickapoo Indians.; Koasati Indians.; Modoc Indians.; Modoc Indians--Wars, 1873.; Ojibwa Indians.; Osage Indians.; Ottawa Indians.; Potawatomi Indians.; Sauk Indians.; Seminole Indians.; Seneca Indians.; Shawnee Indians.; Tonkawa Indians.; Tonkawa language.; Wea Indians.; Wichita Indians.; Winnebago Indians.; Wyandot Indians.; Yamassee Indians.; Yamassee Indians--Wars.
Places:
Fort Colville (Wash.); Fort Ellis (Mont.); Fort Laramie (Wyo.); Fort Pierre (S.D.); Fort Smith (Ark.); Neah Bay (Wash.); Nooksack River (Wash.); Sac & Fox Nation of Missouri in Kansas and Nebraska.; Tulalip Indian Reservation (Wash.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Detailed printed guide (Folder 0)
  This guide is available by clicking here.
- General information (Folder 1)
  Pages G1-G81
- Albert Pike (Folder 2)
  Pages P1-P192
- Washington and Oregon Territories (Folder 3)
  Pages W+O1-W+O90
- St. Louis and Michigan Districts (Folder 4)
  Pages S1-S270
- Red Cloud Agency (Folder 5)
  Pages R1-R264
- Colonel Return J. Meigs, December 28, 1802 - December 31, 1812 (Folder 6)
  Pages M1-M177
- Colonel Return J. Meigs, July 1813 - February 1823 (Folder 7)
  Pages M178-M356
- Cherokee, not including Meigs, 1798 - 1823 (Folder 8)
  Pages C1-C245
- Cherokee, 1831 - 1837, 1842 - 1846, 1861 - 1863, undated (Folder 9)
  Pages C246-C507
- Western Territory, not including Meigs and Cherokee (Folder 10)
  Pages W1-W152
- Reports Western Territory, December 1831 - December 1834 (Folder 11)
  Pages 1-189